

Technology Consultant m.swaraj.jobs@gmail.com 7980006845 Kolkata

Date of birth 12 Dec 1994

Nationality Indian

SWARAJ MANDAL

Profile

As a **Zuora** Billing Consultant with experience at EY, I have been involved in implementing and managing billing systems for clients. With an MBA from Globsyn Business School and a Bachelor of Technology degree from Hooghly Engineering & Technology College, I bring a strong educational background to my work. My future goals include continuing to expand my knowledge and skills in the field of billing and consulting.

Employment History

Associate Consultant at Ernst & Young, Bangalore

08/2022-Present

Zuora Billing Consultant

- I am responsible for providing expert guidance and support to clients in implementing and optimizing the Zuora billing platform, collaborate with cross-functional teams to understand client requirements and design customized solutions that meet their business needs.
- I have technical expertises in Zuora like Data Query, SQL, ZOQL, Liquid coding in workflows, Invoice template customization using HTML, APEX coding in CPQ, Rules and plug ins in Zuora CPQ, Flow triggers, Zuora Billing and CPQ Object Models Experience in translating client requirements into technical specifications and solution design.
- I have a strong understanding of subscription-based billing models and leverage my knowledge to configure and integrate Zuora with other systems. I also provide support to client teams to ensure smooth adoption and utilization of the platform.

Risk Management Analyst

- I was responsible for finishing the initial inspection and submission of client requests following a careful assessment of accuracy and timeliness in accordance with established standards.
- Acts as a link between global client teams, other members of the RMS team, and various functional departments within the company.
- Manage the Global Personal Independence Compliance Testing program and maintain and deploy associated work programs.
- Review audit workpapers and findings, where appropriate and record regulatory independence violations/breaches of the IESBA Code of Ethics as well as local professional standards in the Independence Consultation Database.
- Review and agree on findings with auditees and complete required audits and communicate the results to the respective auditees on a timely basis.

Data Analyst Associate at IIMI Image Management Pvt Ltd, Kolkata

08/2019-03/2020

- Developed a data ingestion process to automate the transfer of data from multiple sources into a single database, resulting in a reduction in manual data entry.
- Created comprehensive reports and data visualizations using advanced Excel and Tableau, effectively communicating complex findings to stakeholders and supporting data-driven decision-making.
- Developed and implemented databases, data collection, data analysis and other strategies that optimized statistical efficiency and quality

Skills

Zuora Billing	5/5
Billing Implementation	5/5
Zuora Revenue	3/5
Revenue Implementation	3/5
Configure Price Quote (CPQ)	5/5
C++	
MS Office	5/5
SQL	
MySQL	3/5
Anaplan	
Salesforce	3/5
Power BI	
Tableau	2/5
Azure	2/5
AWS	
Google Cloud Platform	2/5

Certifications

Zuora Billing Delivery Architect, Zuora University 05/2023

Zuora Billing Analyst, Zuora University 09/2022

Anaplan Level 1 Model Builder (L1), Anaplan 06/2023

Anaplan Level 2 Model Builder (L2), Anaplan 02/2024

Salesforce Certified Associate, Salesforce 06/2023

Salesforce Certified Administrator, Salesforce 02/2024

Cloud Fusion Analytics Warehouse (FAW), Oracle 08/2023

Education

MBA/PGDM, Globsyn Business School, Kolkata

08/2020-08/2022

Specialization in Finance (Major) & Information Systems (Minor) and Graduated with 68.77%

Bachelor of Technology, Hooghly Engineering & Technology College, Hooghly

08/2012-08/2016

Specialization in Electrical Engineering and Graduated with 68.30%

12th Senior Secondary Education, Kendriya Vidyalaya O.F. Dum Dum (CBSE), Kolkata

2012

Specialization in Computer Science and Passed with 66%

10th Secondary Education, Kendriya Vidyalaya O.F. Dum Dum (CBSE), Kolkata

2010

Passed with 83.60%

Internships

Entrepreneurship & Finance Intern at Alma Mater Biz Solutions PLC, Mumbai

05/2021-07/2021

- Collaborated with accounting and finance teams to create monthly and quarterly financial reports
- Analyzed and prepared a business plan and its further development plans including its financial planning, operation strategy, Marketing Strategy and Management and Organization Plans
- Researched and wrote articles on a variety of topics, including lifestyle, business, technology, and finance

Inplant Electrical Trainee at Mother Dairy Calcutta, Kolkata

06/2015-07/2015

- Performed mechanical and electrical assembly, including wiring and soldering.
- Got trained in Quality control, process engineering, Packaging and Administration under the guidance of Senior Officials.

Languages

	Good working knowledge
Hindi	Native speaker
Bengali	Native speaker

Hobbies

Driving Trekking Camping Sports